<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-h-h-holmes</id>
    <results>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84036012/1894-11-19/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          By the death of R. H. Holmes, alias Howard, in Boston, a gigantic swindling scheme has been unearthed by the detectives of the Fidelity Mutual Life Insurance association of
          this city. On Sept. 3 last the corpse of a man was found at 1316 Callow Hill Street, in this city, and was buried by the coroner under the name of H. J. Pitzel. Now it 
          appears that the corpse was a bold substitute for the purpose of defrauding the insurance company of $10,000. Attorney Howe of St. Louis appeared in Philadelphia, accompanied 
          by a young girl, whom he represented as a daughter of the dead man. It was decided by the insurance company to exhume the body, which was done by the officials of the 
          company. The officials were satisfied, and the body was reburied, and Attorney Howe received $10,000, representing the sum due Mrs. Pitzel. A month ago one of the 
          company's agents, while in St. Louis, became cognizant of some of the facts and formulated the story of the conspiracy. He discovered Holmes and Howe had been related in the 
          character of lawyer and client in a case where Holmes had been arrested under the name of H. M. Howard for obtaining goods under false pretenses. Then it was found that Holmes 
          and Pitzel had been in business together in Chicago during the World's Fair, where they conducted a hotel with secret rooms in which they hid goods obtained by swindling 
          merchants. The place was called World's Fair Hotel. While here Pitzel took out a policy with the Fidelity company, and Holmes followed his example a month later, both giving 
          notes for the first payment. Holmes was chased all over the country. It was learned that Pitzel and Holmes obtained, by some means or other, a corpse from the New York 
          hospital, brought it here, surrounded it by the evidence of the incidents of death in the Callow Hill street house, and obtained the $10,000. Holmes was arrested in Boston by 
          detectives, who are now after the other conspirator.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1894-11-21/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The arch conspirator, H. H. Holmes, accompanied by Mrs. Pitzel and a pretty woman who calls herself Mrs. Holmes, arrived in this city today in the 
	  custody of Detective Crawford and Special Agent Perry of the Fidelity Mutual Life association. Mrs. Pitzel's 16-year-old daughter, Meda, and her 1-year-old baby were also with 
	  the party. Mrs. Holmes disappeared soon after her arrival, and no clue to her whereabouts could be obtained. It is thought she is stopping at a hotel in the neighborhood of 
	  police headquarters. After the arrival, the party was closeted with Superintendent of Police Linden until late in the afternoon. When the conference was over, Detective 
	  Crawford detailed the story of the trip, the most important feature of which was the relation by Mr. Holmes of the story of his whole life. It reads like the most sensational 
	  of romances.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042461/1894-11-22/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The Pitzel mystery deepens as time wears on. Today many theories in regard to the mystery were knocked in the head by the announcement that B. F. 
	  Pitzel, the supposed murdered man, was seen in Chicago less than two weeks ago. President Fouz of the Fidelity Life Insurance company said today: "This morning my Chicago 
	  representative telegraphed me that a Mr. Bryan, who is a business man in Chicago, called on him and said that B. F. Pitzel was in that city less than two weeks ago. Mr. Bryan 
	  says he has known Pitzel for many years, and had frequent business transactions with him, and it is impossible for him to be mistaken. When they met, Bryan did not know Pitzel 
	  was supposed to be dead, and the two greeted each other cordially and repaired to a nearby saloon where they had a drink together. Then they separated, and Bryan says he does 
	  not know whether Pitzel was to remain in the city or not. However, our men there and the Pinkerton detectives have taken up the clew, and it is my opinion that Pitzel will be 
	  produced within a few days."
          
          This information raises questions about the supposed death of Pitzel, Holmes’ role in the fraud, and potential additional victims tied to Holmes’ schemes.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1895-07-16/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          The bodies of Etta, Alice and Hettie Pietzel, the missing daughters of Benjamin F. Pietzel, were found by Detective Cuddy of Toronto and Detective 
	  Greyer of Philadelphia, to-day, buried in the cellar of the house No. 16 St. Vincent street. H. H. Holmes, now under arrest at Philadelphia, is believed to have deliberately 
	  murdered the girls after he had first murdered their father in Philadelphia and their brother in Detroit.

          Inquiries began by the police to-day and led to the knowledge that Holmes and the children lived at the house in question, and search was made by the two officers. A 
	  photograph of Holmes was shown to Frank N. Nudel of the Ontario Educational Department, who owns No. 16 St. Vincent street, and without hesitation he identified it as that of 
	  the man who had rented the house from him last October, and after a very short stay had departed.

          When they reached the cellar it appeared to the detectives that something had disturbed the cellar floor, and arming themselves with shovels they began to dig. A short 
	  distance below the surface they came across the arm and a portion at the head of one of the girls, and further work soon revealed the bodies of all of the victims. They were 
	  nude and apparently had lain there since last October.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
        <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1895-07-28/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
        <text>
          More conclusive evidence than has heretofore been collected by the police in the Holmes case was revealed by the investigation tonight. Inspector 
	  Fitzpatrick believes it to be certain that at least three murders were committed in the “castle” of Holmes. A witness revealed that Holmes had hired him to mount three 
	  skeletons taken from victims’ bodies in his house. Further discoveries of quicklime graves and remnants of two women’s remains solidify these claims.

          Key details include the use of articulated skeletons for supposed medical purposes, with flesh removed under suspicious circumstances, and corroborating testimonies linking 
	  Holmes to gruesome acts. The narrative follows Holmes’ pattern of leveraging murder for monetary or logistical gains while maintaining secrecy about the fates of his victims.

          Holmes’ network and actions, such as a letter detailing evasive instructions to accomplices, reflect a calculated attempt to cover his crimes. Continued revelations 
	  underscore his deliberate and methodical approach to homicide.
        </text>
      </result>
      <result>
  	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn82014635/1895-08-03/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
  	<rel>1</rel>
  	<text>
    	  The Holmes case took a new turn as Pat Quinlan, janitor of the "Castle," was believed to have made a partial confession implicating H. H. Holmes in the 
	  murder of Benjamin F. Pietzel and other crimes. According to police sources, Quinlan signed a written confession, providing details on Pietzel's murder and shedding light on 
	  Holmes' swindling operations.

    	  Investigators also examined the connections between Holmes and other alleged victims, such as Minnie Williams and Emeline Cigrand. Some evidence pointed to 
	  Holmes' involvement in a network of illegal activities, including selling dismembered bodies to medical schools and grave-robbing in Michigan. Additional witness accounts, 
	  including those from expressmen and "bone riggers," further corroborated Holmes' operations within the Castle.

          Of particular interest were the reports that bodies were chemically treated and packaged, with Quinlan admitting to facilitating this grisly business. Law enforcement 
	  continued excavations in the Castle basement in search of remains. Authorities believe Quinlan's confession may lead to stronger evidence and eventual conviction of Holmes.

          The case, already infamous for its macabre details, continued to reveal more shocking aspects of Holmes' crimes, including fraudulent insurance schemes and methods used to 
	  dispose of bodies. The developments, alongside testimony from witnesses like Minnie Williams' lawyer and Quinlan's wife, brought new urgency to the investigation.

          This marked a critical phase in the unraveling of Holmes' criminal empire, as investigators pursued leads with the expectation of formally charging Holmes with multiple 
	  murders.
  	</text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1896-05-08/ed-1/?sp=1</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        H.H. Holmes, born Herman W. Mudgett, was executed on May 7, 1896, in Philadelphia for the murder of Benjamin F. Pietzel. Holmes remained calm and indifferent to his fate, 
	denying guilt for several crimes attributed to him, including the murder of Pietzel's children. Known for his infamous "Murder Castle" in Chicago, he had confessed to 27 
	murders, although many claims were later disproven. Holmes' body was encased in cement to prevent grave robbery, per his own instructions. The execution brought an end to the 
	life of one of America’s most notorious criminals.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn98066406/1914-03-12/ed-1/?sp=6&amp</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        Patrick Quinlan, a carpenter who worked on H.H. Holmes' infamous "Murder Castle" in Chicago, died by suicide in Portland, Michigan, in March 1914. Before his death, 
        Quinlan reportedly expressed an inability to sleep, potentially linked to his knowledge of the "Castle's" sinister traps, false partitions, and hidden features. Although 
        suspected as a possible accomplice, Quinlan was released without charges. His death adds a mysterious postscript to the Holmes case, as he was one of the few who might 
        have uncovered more details about the building’s dark history.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84024441/1895-10-28/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        On October 28, 1895, Herman W. Mudgett, better known as H.H. Holmes, stood trial in Philadelphia for the murder of Benjamin F. Pitezel. Holmes, notorious for his 
        macabre crimes, was accused not only of murdering Pitezel but also of killing Pitezel’s children and other victims connected to his infamous "Murder Castle" in Chicago. 

        Pitezel's death in 1894 was initially ruled an accident caused by an oil lamp explosion. However, suspicions from the insurance company that paid out $10,000 on 
        Pitezel’s policy led to an investigation and Holmes' arrest. During the investigation, detectives discovered the bodies of Pitezel’s children in Toronto and Irvington, 
        Indiana. 

        Holmes’ trial began under unusual circumstances, with his defense lawyers resigning. Holmes chose to represent himself, refusing court-appointed attorneys. The 
        trial exposed Holmes' intricate insurance fraud schemes and his chilling pattern of murder. Holmes’ notoriety stems from his use of the "Murder Castle," a building 
        designed with traps and hidden rooms to carry out his crimes and dispose of victims.

        Despite his claims of innocence, Holmes' actions and mounting evidence cemented his legacy as one of the most infamous criminals of his era.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1914-07-04/ed-1/?sp=19&amp</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        On July 4, 1914, Patrick Quinlan, the former janitor and caretaker of H.H. Holmes' infamous "Murder Castle," was found dead in his home in Portland, Michigan. He 
        had taken poison, leaving a note that read, "I could not sleep," signaling nearly two decades of psychological torment. Quinlan had unknowingly helped construct the 
        Murder Castle, a building in Chicago outfitted with secret trapdoors, asbestos-lined rooms, and a massive furnace, all designed to aid Holmes' horrific murders.

        Holmes, whose real name was Herman W. Mudgett, used the Murder Castle during the 1893 World's Fair to carry out numerous killings. Victims included visitors to 
        Chicago and individuals enticed to the Castle under false pretenses. The building featured soundproofed chambers and hidden disposal systems, including vats of 
        quicklime and a large stove to incinerate bodies.

        Holmes' crimes first came to light after the suspicious death of Benjamin F. Pitezel, whose life insurance Holmes fraudulently claimed. Investigations led to the 
        discovery of the bodies of Pitezel’s children and other victims, and Holmes was ultimately arrested, tried, and hanged in 1896. Quinlan, though exonerated of any 
        involvement in the murders, lived the rest of his life haunted by his association with Holmes and the gruesome events in the Castle.

        The story of Quinlan's tragic end serves as a chilling reminder of the enduring impact of Holmes' atrocities, which cemented his legacy as one of history's most 
        notorious serial killers.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058130/1888-11-27/ed-1/?sp=1&amp</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058396/1914-07-04/ed-1/?sp=19&amp</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
	Holmes, a con artist and bigamist, believed to have killed between 20 to 200 people. Murders many victims in a specially constructed house in Chicago, Illinois dubbed the 
	“Murder Castle.”
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2020/07/trials-of-the-century-19th-century-edition/</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn90059522/1893-10-13/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.209,-0.071,1.418,1.418,0</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
	<id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn91068504/1921-06-01/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.274,-0.004,1.548,1.548,0</id>
    <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
  </results>
 </topic>
 <topic>
   <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-belle-gunness-murder-farm</id>
     <results>
     <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090383/1908-05-06/ed-1/?sp=1&q=body+La+Belle+Porte+Gunness+bodies</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        Three more new graves supposed to contain the bodies of murder victims were found on the place of Mrs. Belle Gunness today. The sheriff and a number of 
	deputies are digging out these graves to get at their secrets. The belief is general that Mrs. Gunness is not dead but that another body has been substituted for her and that 
	she is probably on her way to Norway. The head of the body supposed to be Mrs. Gunness is missing. The sheriff holds to the opinion that some of the bodies already unearthed 
	here are victims of murder in Chicago and that they were shipped here to hide the crimes.
	      
        Anton Olson today identified the body found yesterday as that of his daughter Jennie. The head had been cut from the trunk and the body was badly mutilated. Mrs. Christoforson, 
	a neighbor of Mrs. Gunness, told the sheriff today that three men who had lived at the Gunness home within the last year had disappeared. The neighbors suspected foul play at 
	the time, but in each case Mrs. Gunness told the neighbors that the men had answered matrimonial advertisements and that she was not pleased with them. The officers now hope 
	to have Roy Lamphere confess shortly. He is said to have admitted running from the Gunness farm shortly after the fire started.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85052114/1908-05-08/ed-1/?sp=2&q=body+Matrimonial+Belle+matrimonial+Gun+bodies</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        More Bodies Brought to Light Buried on Farm of Female Blue Beard Near La Porte, Ind.

        United States District Attorney Sims ordered the arrest of every manager of any matrimonial bureau in Chicago following the revelations made in connection with 
	the Gunness house of horror at La Porte.

        Digging in Chicago.

        The police department today began digging in the yard of the place occupied by Mrs. Gunness while she lived here at 618 Alma Street, expecting to find bodies. It is believed 
	she practiced her profession here.

        Mrs. Belle Gunness of La Porte, Ind., bought her poisons in Chicago. She was positively identified from several of her photographs and her official description 
	as a woman who was frequently seen in the neighborhood of Wabash Avenue and Harrison Street as recently as four months ago and who attempted to purchase morphine in a drug 
	store at No. 309 Wabash Avenue.

        More Bodies Found.

        Shortly after the search for bodies buried at the Gunness farm was resumed today, another skeleton, making the tenth unearthed since Tuesday, was 
	discovered. It is impossible to determine the sex of the victim. Another confused mass of bones was found later. The sheriff believes the grave contains two bodies. 
	Decomposition has gone so far it is difficult to tell whether there are one or two bodies in the grave.

        Several bones of another body were found shortly before noon two feet from those first found today. This makes three bodies uncovered today and twelve since Thursday. Beside 
	the last batch of bones, which showed burn signs, a metal frame of a woman's pocketbook was found. Efforts are being made today to find the skull of the woman's body in the 
	ruins of the house. Ashes in the cellar are to be screened in the effort to find some part of the skull.

        Maxson, a farmhand, says Mrs. Gunness had planned to have a power garden this year on the spot where most of the bodies were found.

        The first skeleton lay in a wooden box three feet under the surface. Other bones are a few feet away. A pair of women's shoes were in the box. They were heavy; part of the 
	shoes were burned. Some bones showed signs of fire. The body in the box had been dismembered exactly in the same way as those found before.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063756/1908-05-08/ed-1/?sp=1&q=farm+Belle+death+Gunness</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        One of the most gruesome murder mysteries ever unearthed in that section of the country came to light Tuesday when the bodies of five persons, all of them murdered, were found 
	in the yard of the home of Mrs. Belle Gunness, who, with three of her children, was burned to death on the night of April 28.

        So far, only two of the bodies have been identified. These are Andrew Helgelein, who came to that city from Aberdeen, S.D., for the purpose of marrying Mrs. Gunness, whose 
	acquaintance he had made through a matrimonial bureau. The other is that of Jennie Olson Gunness, a Chicago girl, who had been adopted by Mrs. Gunness. She disappeared in 
	September 1906, and it was said had gone to Los Angeles to attend school. The other bodies were those of a man and two children, apparently 13 years old.

        The body of Helgelein was dismembered, and the arms, legs, trunk, and head were buried in different parts of the yard. It is believed by the authorities that Guy Lamphere, who 
	has been under arrest since the burning of the Gunness home, on the charge of murdering Mrs. Gunness and her family, committed the Helgelein crime. Lamphere is a carpenter, and 
	the manner in which the body of Helgelein was dismembered leads to the belief that it was done by somebody familiar with the use of a saw.

        Evidence tending to show that the nine dismembered corpses unearthed Tuesday and Wednesday had been shipped to La Porte, probably from Chicago, came to light. The testimony of 
	draymen who had carted trunks and boxes to the Gunness home lent color to this supposition. The La Porte police also received information that two trunks, consigned to 
	"Mrs. Belle Gunness, La Porte, Ind.," are held in an express office in Chicago.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1908-05-10/ed-1/?sp=1&q=murder+murderer+Belle+Gunness+murdered+MURDER+human+Murder+bodies</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        There is no better way of indicating the demoniacal qualities now generally ascribed to Mrs. Belle Gunness hereabouts than by saying that when it was 
	announced at nightfall today that no more bodies had been dug up in that garden of death on the Gunness place, everybody in Laporte was surprised.

	Always suspected and feared during her lifetime, the woman has now become in the public mind a paragon of bloodlust, craft, and treachery. Apparently, nobody would be shocked 
	to learn that every square yard of her fifty-acre farm is sown with the bodies of her victims.

        Meanwhile, certain things stand out as hard and brutal facts: since the little boys got to work with their spades five days ago, they have uncovered what the doctors say are 
	the remnants of ten human bodies. Four of these were found in a pit about four feet square. Only three have been identified with certainty, including Andrew Heigellin and Ole 
	Budsberg, who were lured with marriage promises. The remaining six victims are still unidentified.

        Belle Gunness’s story has shocked the nation, and the ongoing investigations into her "murder farm" reveal the depth of her crimes.
      </text> 
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn95069780/1908-05-14/ed-1/?sp=3&q=murder+Lamphere+Gunness+Gun+guns+CHRONOLOGY+murders+Guns</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        Wholesale murder, more ruthlessly premeditated and diabolically executed than the famous Holmes Castle crimes in Chicago, was revealed at Laporte, Ind., Tuesday when five 
	mutilated bodies were dug up in the backyard of the home of Mrs. Belle Gunness, who together with her three children, is supposed to have met death when their house burned one 
	week before.

        Fifteen persons already have a place on the list of known or probably slain, and circumstances point to Mrs. Gunness as the arch-conspirator in at least twelve of the crimes. 
	It had been accepted as true that she and her three children had met death in the fire that destroyed their home, but now suspicion arises that the bodies found in the 
	smoldering ruins were brought from a hospital or medical school to create the belief that Mrs. Gunness and her family had perished.

        Among the victims identified were Andrew Helgeloin of Aberdeen, S.D., who disappeared after loaning Mrs. Gunness $1,500, and Jennie Olson, the adopted daughter of Mrs. Gunness, 
	who was said to have left to attend school in Los Angeles. Several unidentified bodies, including children, were also discovered.

        Mrs. Gunness reportedly used matrimonial advertisements to lure her victims and may have staged the fire to cover up her crimes. The arrests and evidence suggest a methodical 
	pattern of murder for financial gain, as well as efforts to deceive authorities.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn84028490/1908-05-22/ed-1/?sp=1&q=murder+Belle+Gunness+murdeiess+Insured+murders+Insurance</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        The case of Belle Gunness, the so-called "murderess" of Laporte, Indiana, remains a subject of significant mystery and investigation. Lawyers for Ray Lamphere, accused of arson 
	and complicity in multiple murders, claim Belle Gunness might still be alive. However, local coroner Mack insists her charred body was found in the ruins of the fire, though 
	the identity is still debated due to conflicting evidence such as her teeth.

        Several witnesses, including attorneys and local residents, provided statements either supporting the possibility of Gunness's escape or verifying the identification of the 
	body. Meanwhile, the case grows more complex as victims' families, such as those of Andrew Helgelein and Jennie Olson, demand answers about their loved ones' gruesome deaths on 
	the Gunness property.

        The grand jury continues to work on indictments for Lamphere, including six counts related to arson and multiple homicides. Authorities have received tips from across the 
	country, further complicating the investigation.

        This case has drawn nationwide attention due to the alleged crimes' brutality, financial motivations, and the sensational nature of the investigation.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86069458/1908-05-28/ed-1/?sp=3&q=fire+BELLE+GUNNESS</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        The case of Belle Gunness, the infamous "murderess" of Laporte, Indiana, continues to unravel with new discoveries and grim revelations. Ray Lamphere, a former farmhand accused 
	of arson and potential involvement in the murders, maintains his innocence. He claims to have been aware of suspicious activities on the Gunness property but denies 
	participation in any crimes.

        The fire at the Gunness farmhouse led to the discovery of nine buried bodies and three charred children's remains, initially identified as Gunness' own children. A headless 
	adult female body, believed at first to be Gunness herself, raises doubts among investigators due to inconsistencies such as her distinctive gold dental work.

        Victims such as Andrew Helgelein, who was lured to the farm with promises of matrimony and subsequently disappeared, were unearthed. He had withdrawn $3,000 shortly before his 
	death, pointing to financial motives behind the murders. Other victims included Jennie Olson, the adopted daughter of Gunness, whose body was found among the graves, and other 
	unidentified remains.

        Authorities, including Coroner Dr. C. F. Mack, continue to investigate the case, taking meticulous notes and examining the remains. Meanwhile, suspicions grow that Gunness 
	staged the fire and used the headless body as a decoy to fake her death and escape justice.

        The case has captured national attention, not only for its gruesome nature but also for the questions surrounding Gunness' possible survival and escape. Witness accounts, 
	forensic evidence, and Lamphere's testimony are key to uncovering the full scope of this chilling mystery.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88085190/1908-07-11/ed-1/?sp=6&q=FARM+Belle+DEATH+Gunness</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        The case of Belle Gunness, the notorious "murderess" of La Porte, Indiana, remains one of the most chilling criminal stories of the era. Her farm became infamous as authorities 
	unearthed the remains of numerous victims following a fire that destroyed her home. Among the findings were three charred children's bodies, identified as her own, and the 
	headless body of an adult woman initially thought to be Gunness.

        Gunness allegedly lured men with matrimonial ads, convincing them to bring their wealth to her farm before killing them. Notable victims included Andrew Helgelein, 
	who withdrew $3,000 before visiting the farm, and Jennie Olson, her adopted daughter, whose body was also found buried on the property.

        Questions linger about Gunness’ fate. Investigators suspect she staged her death by using the headless body as a decoy, possibly escaping to avoid justice. Witness testimonies, 
	forensic evidence, and suspicions of her use of quicklime to dissolve evidence add to the mystery.

        Ray Lamphere, a former farmhand, was charged with arson and complicity. He denied direct involvement in the murders but claimed knowledge of the suspicious activities at the 
	farm. Coroner Dr. C. F. Mack and other authorities continue their detailed investigations, piecing together evidence to understand the extent of the crimes.

        The shocking details of the case, including the methodical disposal of victims and the possibility of Gunness’ escape, have captured the nation's attention, leaving behind a 
	haunting legacy of murder, greed, and deception.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn87062268/1908-11-27/ed-1/?sp=1&q=LAMPHERE+ARSON+arson+guilty+GUILTY+RAY</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        Ray Lamphere, the former farmhand of Belle Gunness, was found guilty of arson in connection with the fire that destroyed the Gunness farmhouse on April 20, 1908. The 
	jury reached a verdict after deliberating since the previous day, convicting Lamphere of setting the fire but not of murder. The case revolved around the blaze that 
	uncovered the shocking crimes at the Gunness property, including the discovery of multiple buried bodies and the charred remains of three children. Lamphere's defense 
	argued that the charge was inconsistent, suggesting that if he were guilty, it would be for a more severe offense like murder. Attorney Worden for the defense expressed 
	his dissatisfaction with the verdict, labeling it "ridiculous." He announced plans to file a motion for a new trial and, if necessary, appeal to the Indiana Supreme 
	Court. Judge Richter sentenced Lamphere to an indeterminate term of two to twenty years in the state penitentiary at Michigan City. Despite the outcome, questions 
	linger about Lamphere's role in the broader scheme of Belle Gunness’ alleged crimes. Gunness, the suspected "murderess" of multiple victims lured to her farm under the 
	guise of marriage, is believed by some to have staged her death to escape justice. The case has captivated the public with its sensational elements, including 
	Gunness’ alleged financial motives, her potential escape, and Lamphere's claims of innocence. As the defense prepares its appeal, the trial's implications and the 
	mysteries of the Gunness property continue to unfold.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058245/1908-12-03/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Belle+Gunness</id>
      <rel>1</rel>
      <text>
        Ray Lamphere, the man accused of setting fire to Belle Gunness’ home on April 28, 1908, was found guilty of arson. The jury’s decision was seen as a compromise, as some jurors 
	reportedly pushed for a murder conviction, while others held out for lesser charges. Lamphere was sentenced to an indeterminate term of two to twenty-one years in the Michigan 
	City state prison, fined $5,000, and stripped of his voting rights for five years.

        His defense attorney, Worden, announced plans to appeal the verdict, arguing that Lamphere’s conviction for arson was inconsistent with the charges and evidence. If the case 
	is retried, it could focus on one of the other charges against Lamphere, such as the murder of Andrew Helgelein, whose body was among those unearthed on the Gunness property.

        The trial has drawn widespread attention, as the fire revealed a gruesome series of murders tied to Belle Gunness. Victims, including Helgelein and others lured by promises of 
	marriage, were found buried on the farm. The case remains infamous for its chilling details and the unresolved question of whether Gunness faked her death to escape justice.

        The jury’s deliberations highlighted the complexity of the case and the difficulty of assigning guilt in the absence of direct evidence tying Lamphere to the murders. The 
	sentence reflects a middle ground, punishing Lamphere for his involvement in the fire while leaving questions about the broader crimes unanswered.
      </text>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://blogs.loc.gov/loc/2022/02/the-murders-at-the-metropolitan-opera-crime-classics-latest/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/wpalh3.33031510/?st=text</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn88076526/1922-11-08/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.175,-0.067,1.349,1.349,0</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/01001167/</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>
    <result>
      <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn89065027/1908-02-19/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.331,-0.083,1.663,1.663,0</id>
      <rel>0</rel>
    </result>    
 </results>
</topic>
<topic>
   <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-johnson-vs-jeffries</id>
    <results>
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1910-06-26/ed-1/?sp=36&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
         The all-absorbing topic in the sporting world just now is the approaching forty-five round battle between Jack Johnson and Jim Jeffries. As was to be expected, Jeffries is 
	 the favorite in the betting at odds of 10 to 7, but this in reality is more a question of sentiment than cool, unbiased judgment. Men who make a close study of prizefights 
	 and their form are not so prone to risk their dollars on the white man, who has been out of the game as long as Jeff. Then too, they realize that in Johnson he will face a 
	 strong, husky, clever, and hard-hitting man.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1910-07-03/ed-1/?sp=47&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
	 Champion Jack Johnson covered over eight miles on the Lawton Springs road today after a morning spent in revelry and rest. In order to bring himself to the 
	 finest point of condition before entering the ring, he will probably continue the limbering-up process until the last minute, doing slight road work tomorrow afternoon with 
	 his trainers.

         As was the case yesterday, a great number of well-known pugs and men prominent in the sporting realm kept the roadhouse lively today. The champion arose shortly after 7 
	 o'clock, and when breakfast was over, he left the resort for Reno, accompanied by a number of his trainers and intimate friends. He visited the arena and spent a short while 
	 riding through the town before returning. Contrary to his program of the last two days, he remained downstairs and mixed in the sports of his crew, shooting an exciting game 
	 of craps on the porch and presiding as judge at a mock trial for the benefit of the moving picture men.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85038615/1910-07-03/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
	 The end is almost in sight now. All that outdoor work or indoor work can do for Jim Jeffries and Jack Johnson has been done. They may sprint or stroll, 
	 but for long-distance trudging, the dusty highways will know them no more. To-day, the punching bags are dangling unmolested, and the bruised faces of sparring partners are 
	 being given an opportunity to heal. It is taken for granted that the rival heavyweights are in good condition and that nothing growing out of the men’s preparation for the 
	 big fight has been withheld.

	 On one point, there is more unanimity than there was even a month ago. It is felt that it will be a square fight—a bitter struggle between two men, to each of whom victory 
	 means more than it ever meant before. It is further agreed that the better man will not be cramped in his efforts to win. When the match was first made, I heard men say: 
	 "I'd hate to be in Johnson's shoes if he is winning." The inference was that no crowd would stand for seeing the hope of the white race battered down by a negro. Not so long 
	 ago, the same kind of talk was still being heard, and it had its effect on Johnson. He asked Tex Rickard to provide him with ample protection in the shape of determined men 
	 in case he showed himself superior to big Jim Jeffries. Personally, I do not believe that Johnson's head would have been injured, no matter where the event took place. But 
	 once the two fighters came in over the borders of Nevada, the event ceased to be the "clash of the races," and Johnson's spirits rose. He feels that in this section, his 
	 complexion or his race will cut no figure. The winner will be cheered, and the loser will not be a mark for execration.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83030214/1910-07-03/ed-1/?sp=8&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
	 Reno is just waiting now for the moment when Billy Jordan, the announcer, will climb out of the ring with all the speed that his fat legs can carry him, crying, "Let 'er go." 
	 Another languid sunset in these brown hills, and the great Jeffries-Johnson battle will be on. In the meantime, the desert city is taking on the appearance of a national 
	 convention. The delegates from the world's sporting centers are arriving on every train. The streets and hotels are filled with a shifting mob of men from all walks of life. 
	 The hum of conversation on the street is punctuated with the click of the roulette wheels  and with the cry of souvenir hawkers. And all are awaiting the fight that nothing 
	 but an earthquake, fire, or death can now prevent. The camps of the fighters are quiet, with the quiet of suspense. The arena, fully completed, is waiting out in the white 
	 dust, an ugly skeleton that in a few hours will be palpitating with life and the thrills that run down men’s spines in moments of physical strife. Probably not another stick 
	 will have to be touched. The purse money is up—all of the sum of $101,000—which the fight lovers will pay Jim Jeffries and Jack Johnson to measure their sinews, their brains, 
	 and their fighting hearts. The only movement from the rival camps today was in the way of pleasure and thought-killing. Both Jeffries and Johnson made automobile trips into 
	 town—Johnson just for fun and to have the crowd stare at him, and Jeffries because he had to, in order to get to the fishing grounds that he decided to visit late in the 
	 afternoon. The critical time of waiting is being watched closely by fight experts. Jeffries has surprised them all by his apparent unconcern on the eve of the greatest battle 
	 of his life. Nothing else was expected from the negro, who thinks only of the moment. To the sporting men who made the trip to Moana Springs in the early afternoon, a restful 
	 scene was presented. On the lawn at the side of the white cottage sat Jeffries and his cronies around a small table. The fighter had on a soft shirt, and a soft cap rested 
	 carelessly on the back of his head. He was leaning over a hand of cards, figuring how to win a few cents from his opponents. When he succeeded, he was happy, and his laugh 
	 rang out so that the crowds hanging over the fence marked “private” smiled in sympathy. Over the group, a great willow tree spread its restful branches. From a branch hung a 
	 cage with two pigeons. On the green lawn, a tiny white dog played, running occasionally to lick the hand of Jeffries. 
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058394/1910-07-03/ed-1/?sp=2&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
	 Jeffries | Johnson
	 Age: 35 | 32
	 Weight: 220 lbs | 214 lbs
	 Height: 6 ft 1½ in | 6 ft 1 in
	 Neck: 18 in | 18 in
	 Chest (normal): 46 in | 39 in
	 Chest (expanded): 49 in | 42 in
	 Biceps: 16 in | 16½ in
	 Forearm: 13 in | 14 in
	 Wrist: 8 in | 10 in
	 Reach: 75 in | 72 in
	 Waist: 36 in | 34 in
	 Thigh: 26½ in | 23 in
	 Calf: 17½ in | 19 in
	 Ankle: 10 in | 9½ in
	 Fights: 20 | 61
	 Losses: 1 | 2
       </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85058398/1910-07-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
	 Today, under the bright Nevada sun, the much-anticipated heavyweight championship fight between James J. Jeffries and John Arthur Johnson took place. By the time the day 
	 ended, Johnson emerged as the world heavyweight champion, knocking out Jeffries in the 15th round.
       </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85052114/1910-07-04/ed-1/?sp=1&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
	 The highly anticipated heavyweight championship fight between James J. Jeffries and Jack Johnson concluded with Johnson securing a decisive victory. The fight ended in the 
	 15th round with Jeffries unable to continue after a series of powerful rights and lefts from Johnson.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn83045433/1910-07-04/ed-1/?sp=9&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
         Born in Carroll, Ohio, on April 15, 1875, Jeffries is thirty-six years old. Known for his immense strength and resilience, Jeffries began boxing accidentally at age eighteen, 
	 defeating Hank Griffin in his debut fight. Over his career, he remained undefeated and captured the World Heavyweight Title from Bob Fitzsimmons in 1899. Jeffries retired 
	 after defeating Jack Munroe in 1904.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85066387/1910-07-05/ed-1/?sp=17&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
         Pears to me like we'll have to get another "hope."
	 The Caucasian that went down to defeat today has carried most of our well wishes for some 18 months past since the day Tommy Burns dropped after 14 rounds to Jack Johnson in 
	 Australia. For three solid months Jeff has been in training at Rowardennan and Moana Springs. He has worked hard and conscientiously, gone on the road, punched the bag, 
	 skipped rope, and broken the ropes of improvised rings in wrestling bouts. He has also done many other gym stunts. Occasionally we would hear of him boxing. Poor Jeffries 
	 found it out today. His judgment of distance was poor, so poor that it occasioned early remarks of derision from the black man. He felt this early himself. Witness his shake 
	 of the head as early as the seventh round. "Discouragement," whispered a man on my right. "He knows he can't win." Jeff realized the futility of timing the black object that 
	 sprang catlike and glided snakelike in front of him. The old eye that timed the "bull rushes of Sharkey, the clever leads of Corbett, and placed pile-driving rights under the 
	 arm of Ruhlin was absent today.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86090383/1910-07-05/ed-1/?sp=5&q=Jack+Johnson+Jeff+Jeffries+big+fight+title</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
         Reno awoke this morning stark fight mad. Even before dawn, the sidewalks were congested. By 7 o'clock, the streets became impassable. Restaurants and dining rooms were packed 
	 with notables, and everywhere the talk was of the fight. Jeffries sent a note to the promoter objecting to the thin floor covering in the ring, claiming it was too slippery. 
	 Arrangements were made to substitute a canvas covering. Jeffries played cards Sunday and retired at 9 p.m., sleeping soundly. Johnson arose early in a playful mood, had light 
	 exercise, and declared himself in fine shape. At 2:30 p.m., Johnson entered the ring to a tremendous ovation, attired in a black and white bathrobe. His seconds accompanied 
	 him. Jeffries entered at 2:32 p.m., receiving an even greater ovation. Wearing short blue trunks and an American flag around his belt, he appeared calm and composed. The 
	 fight began at 2:46 p.m. with no handshake.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063730/1931-07-03/ed-3/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.243,-0.122,1.486,1.582,0</id>
       <rel>0</rel>
     </result>
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/item/17027086/</id>
       <rel>0</rel>
     </result>
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn85042354/1910-07-04/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.29,-0.079,1.579,1.579,0</id>
       <rel>1</rel>
       <text>
         Jack Johnson knocked out Jim Jeffries in the fifteenth round late this afternoon. It was Johnson's fight all the way, he beating up Jeffries unmercifully and finally knocking 
	 him clean out. Johnson was scarcely harmed in the fight, and from the thirteenth had Jeffries wobbly. The first was anybody's round. Johnson struck the first blow, a left to 
	 Jeffries' eye. The round was full of clinching. In the second round there were several blows exchanged, during which Jeffries' eye was slightly marred by Johnson.
	 Johnson forced the fighting in the third round, which made Jeffries cautious. In the fourth round Jeffries started his tactics of playing for Johnson's stomach, on which he 
	 landed several times. Jeff started Johnson's nose bleeding. In the fifth Jeffries drew more claret from Johnson's nose. The sixth round was Johnson's, he beating Jeff's right 
	 eye, almost closing it and drawing blood. Johnson also got the seventh round on points, again opening Jeff's damaged eye. The eighth was also given to Johnson by a slight 
	 shade. The ninth round was marked by hard fighting, in which Jeffries came out on top. They were fighting viciously at the gong. The tenth was also doped out by experts as 
	 Johnson's round. In the eleventh round, Jeffries was bleeding at the nose and mouth. The twelfth was a grueling round, and Jeffries was showing the effect of Johnson pounding 
	 his face. In the thirteenth round, Johnson put it all over Jeffries and had him wobbly at the bell. There hadn't been a knockdown thus far. In the fourteenth round, Johnson 
	 kept up his punishment of Jeffries and knocked him down multiple times. They came to a clinch. Johnson sent a left to the face. Johnson jabbed Jeffries' nose with a left five 
	 times. A series of left and right blows to the jaw put Jeffries out. Jeff went through the ropes. A series of lefts and rights to the jaw knocked Jeffries out completely.
      </text>
     </result> 
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn92070582/1921-07-02/ed-1/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.212,-0.071,1.424,1.424,0</id>
       <rel>0</rel>
     </result>
     <result>
       <id>https://www.loc.gov/resource/sn86063730/1931-07-03/ed-3/?sp=1&st=text&r=-0.243,-0.074,1.486,1.486,0</id>
       <rel>0</rel>
     </result> 
     </results>
</topic>
</topics>
